<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Business Learn Module on PowerApps Test Engine</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/</link><description>Recent content in Business Learn Module on PowerApps Test Engine</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01 - Introduction</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/01-introduction-to-the-business-value-of-automated-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/01-introduction-to-the-business-value-of-automated-testing/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this section , we will explore the business value of automated testing and discuss key concepts and questions that will help you understand its importance. This discussion-focused module will guide you through the maturity model of an organization, existing investments in automated testing, and business motivators.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="understanding-the-business-value">Understanding the Business Value&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Automated testing is not just a technical practice; it has significant business implications. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by discussing the following key concepts:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>02 - Setting Up People and Processes for Success</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/02-setting-up-people-and-processes-for-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/02-setting-up-people-and-processes-for-success/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this section, we will discuss the key elements required to set up people and processes for success in automated testing. This includes identifying the right team members, defining clear roles and responsibilities, and establishing effective processes to ensure smooth implementation and continuous improvement. We will address the needs of two communities: code-first teams incorporating low code in their solutions, and business-driven testing teams creating low code solutions to solve business needs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>03 - Driving Innovation with Low-Code Automated Testing</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/03-driving-innovation-with-low-code-automated-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/03-driving-innovation-with-low-code-automated-testing/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced business environment, innovation is key to staying competitive. Low-code platforms provide a powerful way to rapidly build and deploy solutions by abstracting complexity and leveraging existing functionality and connectors. This approach allows organizations to innovate quickly and efficiently, but to fully realize the benefits of low-code development, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to have a similar speed and agility in creating automated tests.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="benefits-of-low-code-development">Benefits of Low-Code Development&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Low-code platforms, such as Power Platform, enable users to create applications with minimal hand-coding by using visual development tools and pre-built components. This approach offers several benefits:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>04 - Optimizing IT Processes with Low-Code Automated Testing</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/04-optimizing-it-processes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/04-optimizing-it-processes/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s dynamic IT landscape, many organizations have already invested heavily in DevOps processes to streamline their development and deployment workflows. Integrating these existing investments with low-code platforms can further enhance efficiency and innovation. This section will explore how IT teams can extend and integrate their DevOps investments with low-code solutions, focusing on new changes in the Power Platform for Source Control integration, existing connector models for Azure DevOps and GitHub, and the importance of risk and compliance management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>05 - Understanding the High-Level Approvals Process</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/05-understanding-the-high-level-approvals-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/05-understanding-the-high-level-approvals-process/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this section, we will explore the high-level approvals process that supports a team development model with tests. This process ensures that when changes are ready for deployment, they are thoroughly reviewed and approved, leveraging a decentralized model that integrates with business processes and DevOps investments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="team-development-model-with-tests">Team Development Model with Tests&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The team development model involves collaboration across business, IT, and risk teams to build and test solutions. This collaborative approach ensures that solutions meet business needs, are technically sound, and comply with risk and compliance requirements. Key aspects of this model include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>06 - Building a Sustainability Model</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/06-establishing-a-sustainability-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/06-establishing-a-sustainability-model/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the fast-paced world of software development, the initial rush of quickly building and deploying a solution can be exhilarating. However, the true challenge lies in keeping your great idea alive and ensuring its sustainability over time. This module explores how to build a sustainability model that not only keeps your solution relevant but also engages the community and stakeholders in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="starter-discussion-questions">Starter Discussion Questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Consider how you currently ensure the sustainability of your solutions after the initial deployment:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>07 - Growing Solutions to Enterprise Grade</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/07-growing-to-enterprise-grade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/learning/business-path/07-growing-to-enterprise-grade/</guid><description>&lt;p>As your low code solutions scale, the need for robust testing practices becomes more critical. Growing to enterprise-grade involves adopting a model that can deploy on demand and rapidly respond to new features, errors, or security requirements. This model relies on the confidence provided by automated tests, allowing you to meet business needs while adhering to continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD) processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-enterprise-grade-model">The Enterprise-Grade Model&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An enterprise-grade model is designed to handle the complexities and demands of large-scale applications. It ensures that your solutions are sustainable, reliable, secure, and performant, even as they grow in size and complexity. Key components of this model include:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>