<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Roles and Responsibilities in Low Code Testing on PowerApps Test Engine</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/</link><description>Recent content in Roles and Responsibilities in Low Code Testing on PowerApps Test Engine</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Audit</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/audit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/audit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to Audit! Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the roles and responsibilities of audit professionals in the low-code testing landscape on the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into their interests, oversight, and the importance of automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As an audit professional, your primary focus is on ensuring that low-code solutions comply with regulatory requirements and internal policies. You play a crucial role in maintaining an end-to-end audit trail of solutions from idea to delivery. Your responsibilities include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bottom-Up Adoption Strategy</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/bottom-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/bottom-up/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to the Bottom-Up Adoption Strategy! This approach is initiated by individual contributors and teams to drive innovation and adoption from the ground up. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore how this strategy works, its benefits, and how it can be effectively implemented in your organization, especially in the context of adopting automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-bottom-up-adoption">What is Bottom-Up Adoption?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bottom-Up Adoption is a strategy where the initiative to adopt new technologies, such as the Power Platform and automated testing, is driven by individual contributors and teams within the organization. This approach encourages innovation and empowers employees to take the lead in adopting and implementing new solutions. It leverages the creativity and expertise of those who are directly involved in day-to-day operations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Business Stakeholders</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/business-stakeholders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/business-stakeholders/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a business stakeholder, your role is pivotal in ensuring the success of low-code solutions within your organization. You have invested in the Power Platform with the expectation that it will drive business continuity, enhance solution performance, and mitigate security risks. Your oversight is crucial in aligning these solutions with the broader business objectives and ensuring that they deliver the expected value.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="business-continuity">Business Continuity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of your primary concerns is business continuity. You need to ensure that the solutions developed on the Power Platform are reliable and can withstand various operational challenges. Automated testing plays a critical role in this aspect by providing a safety net that ensures new features do not disrupt existing functionality. This continuous validation helps maintain the stability and reliability of the solutions, thereby supporting uninterrupted business operations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Business Unit Leads</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/business-unit-leads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/business-unit-leads/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a Business Unit Lead, your role is critical in bridging the gap between business stakeholders and the teams responsible for developing and deploying low-code solutions. You are tasked with achieving the goals set by business stakeholders while demonstrating the impact and quality of the solutions created. Your oversight ensures that the solutions align with the strategic objectives of the business unit and deliver measurable value.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="achieving-business-goals">Achieving Business Goals&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your primary responsibility is to ensure that the solutions developed on the Power Platform meet the business goals set by stakeholders. This involves overseeing the development process, ensuring that the solutions are aligned with business objectives, and tracking their performance against key metrics. Automated testing plays a vital role in this process by ensuring that the solutions are reliable, performant, and meet the required standards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DevOps Engineers / Architects</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/devops-engineers-architects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/devops-engineers-architects/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to DevOps Engineers and Architects! Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the roles and responsibilities of these key players in the low-code testing landscape on the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore their interests, oversight, and the crucial need for automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a DevOps Engineer or Architect, your primary focus is on the overall Continuous Integration / Deployment (CI/CD) process. You play a pivotal role in integrating the Power Platform into this process, ensuring that everything runs smoothly from development to deployment. Your responsibilities include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enterprise Architects</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/enterprise-architects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/enterprise-architects/</guid><description>&lt;p>As an Enterprise Architect, your role is pivotal in ensuring that the technological landscape of your organization is robust, scalable, and aligned with strategic objectives. You are responsible for reviewing and setting implementation plans for content like the pillars of the &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/powa">Power Well-Architected Framework&lt;/a>, integrating low-code solutions with existing IT investments, and ensuring holistic integration across both low-code and code-first environments. Your oversight ensures that the organization&amp;rsquo;s technology infrastructure supports business goals and drives innovation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Makers</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/makers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/makers/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a Maker, you are at the forefront of innovation within your organization, using low-code tools on the Power Platform to rapidly develop solutions that address business needs. Your role is crucial in driving digital transformation and empowering business users to create impactful applications. However, to ensure the success and sustainability of these solutions, it is essential to incorporate automated testing practices into your development process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="rapid-development">Rapid Development&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of your primary responsibilities is to quickly develop and deploy solutions that meet business requirements. Low-code tools enable you to achieve this by providing a user-friendly interface and pre-built components that simplify the development process. However, rapid development should not come at the expense of quality. Automated testing helps ensure that the solutions you create are reliable and perform as expected, even as you iterate and add new features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managers</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/managers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/managers/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a Manager, your role is crucial in ensuring that your team of makers and software developers has the necessary knowledge and training to effectively build and test low-code solutions on the Power Platform. You are responsible for fostering a culture of continuous learning and improvement, ensuring that your team is equipped to meet the evolving demands of the business.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="knowledge-and-training">Knowledge and Training&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of your primary responsibilities is to ensure that your team has the required knowledge and training to build and test low-code solutions effectively. This involves providing access to training resources, workshops, and hands-on learning opportunities. Automated testing is a critical component of this training, as it equips your team with the skills needed to create reliable and high-quality solutions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microsoft Engineering</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/microsoft-engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/microsoft-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to Microsoft Engineering! Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the roles and responsibilities of Microsoft Engineering teams in the low-code testing landscape on the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into their interests, oversight, and the importance of automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As part of the Microsoft Engineering team, our primary focus is on building and maintaining the features of the Power Platform. We play a crucial role in ensuring that the platform is robust, scalable, and meets the needs of users. Our responsibilities include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microsoft Support</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/microsoft-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/microsoft-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore Microsoft Support teams in relation to low-code testing landscape on the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into our interests, oversight, and the importance of automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As part of the Microsoft Support team, our primary focus is on assisting customers with their Power Platform solutions. We play a crucial role in ensuring that these solutions are reliable, performant, and meet the needs of users. Our responsibilities include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power Customer Advisory Team (Power CAT)</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/powercat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/powercat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to the &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/whoispowercat">Power Customer Advisory Team&lt;/a> (Power CAT)! We are part of the Microsoft Power Platform engineering team, and our mission is to ensure the success of our key enterprise customers with the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into who we are, what we do, and how we interact with various roles to help people be successful, especially in the context of automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="who-we-are">Who We Are&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are a diverse group of technical architects, community managers, program managers, developers, and content creators, located all over the world. Our shared passion for the possibilities of low-code drives us to work closely with a specific group of key enterprise customers, doing whatever it takes to ensure their success with the Power Platform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Architects</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/security-architects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/security-architects/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to Security Architects! Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the roles and responsibilities of security architects in the low-code testing landscape on the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into their interests, oversight, and the importance of automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Security Architect, your primary focus is on managing cybersecurity and data privacy, ensuring that low-code solutions do not expose the organization to risk. You play a crucial role in maintaining the security and compliance of these solutions. Your responsibilities include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software Engineers</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/software-engineers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/software-engineers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to Software Engineers! Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the roles and responsibilities of software engineers in the low-code testing landscape on the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into their interests, oversight, and the importance of automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Software Engineer, your primary focus is on leveraging your code-first skills to enhance and extend the capabilities of the Power Platform. You play a crucial role in integrating traditional development practices with low-code solutions, ensuring that both approaches work seamlessly together. Your responsibilities include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solution Architects</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/solution-architects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/solution-architects/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a Solution Architect, your role is crucial in implementing enterprise standards and making recommendations on how to execute enterprise plans effectively. You are responsible for ensuring that low-code solutions on the Power Platform are built, implemented, reviewed, and deployed in alignment with organizational goals and best practices. Your oversight ensures that these solutions are robust, scalable, and integrated seamlessly into the broader IT ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="implementing-enterprise-standards">Implementing Enterprise Standards&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of your primary responsibilities is to implement enterprise standards that ensure the quality and consistency of low-code solutions. This involves defining best practices for development, testing, and deployment. Automated testing is a key component of these standards, providing a systematic approach to validating the functionality and performance of solutions. By incorporating automated tests, you can ensure that solutions meet the required standards and deliver consistent results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Support Engineers</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/support-engineers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/support-engineers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to Support Engineers! Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the roles and responsibilities of support engineers in the low-code testing landscape on the Power Platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into their interests, oversight, and the importance of automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interests-and-oversight">Interests and Oversight&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a Support Engineer, your primary focus is on ensuring the quality and scalability of low-code solutions across the organization. You play a crucial role in maintaining and supporting these solutions, ensuring they meet the required standards and can be effectively scaled. Your responsibilities include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top-Down Adoption Strategy</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/top-down/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/top-down/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the section dedicated to the Top-Down Adoption Strategy! This approach is driven by leadership and management to ensure alignment with organizational goals. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore how this strategy works, its benefits, and how it can be effectively implemented in your organization, especially in the context of adopting automated testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-top-down-adoption">What is Top-Down Adoption?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Top-Down Adoption is a strategy where the initiative to adopt new technologies, such as the Power Platform and automated testing, is driven by the organization&amp;rsquo;s leadership and management. This approach ensures that the adoption aligns with the overall strategic objectives and goals of the organization. Leadership sets the vision, provides the necessary resources, and drives the adoption process from the top levels of the organization down to individual contributors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trainers</title><link>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/trainers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://microsoft.github.io/PowerApps-TestEngine/roles-and-responsibilities/trainers/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a Trainer, your role is essential in equipping your organization with the skills and knowledge needed to effectively utilize low-code tools on the Power Platform. You are responsible for developing and delivering training programs that empower makers, developers, and other stakeholders to build and test high-quality solutions. Your oversight ensures that the workforce is well-prepared to meet the evolving demands of the business and leverage the full potential of low-code development.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>